I had no idea.
And I mean... since when?
I just thought you're a pretty girl.
So, do you like anyone?
Damn it.
I didn't mean for it to...
Oji-kun!
Um, if what you said back there is true...
I'm really sorry for being
inconsiderate this whole time.
Also, if what you said is true...
I can't reciprocate your feelings.
I'm really sorry.
I know.
I knew... you'd probably
say that, Yoi-san.
That's part of why I like you.
So, let's continue to be work buddies,
all the same.
All right.
Was this... really the right thing to do?
Oh, man...
I sure got rejected.
Yeah?
Yo!
Yoshiko?! I thought you
were in Switzerland!
Heh heh, it's summer break!
What do ya mean, "heh heh"?
How did you find me, anyway?
Auntie told me.
That old hag.
Such a dirty mouth! You're the worst!
I came all the way back to Japan,
and you weren't even home, Kohaku.
And so, I came to you instead!
Oh, gee, thanks.
Later.
Hey!
Is that any way to treat a childhood
friend you haven't seen in forever?!
Anyone who speaks higher than
sixty decibels isn't allowed in.
Huh? Are you telling me I'm loud?!
That's so not true!
I'm so chill, if I were—
Wow!
There's nothing here!
Boring!
I'm telling you right now, I don't
have drinks or anything, all right?
People don't come over, do they?
I hear good fortune stagnates
in a house where no one visits!
Man, wish she'd go home.
Oh, more importantly,
could you go out to dinner with me today?
Huh?
You see,
I went to eat with a friend, and the
guy working there was super hot.
I want to go again today, but it's
embarrassing going by myself, ya know?
So wanna go together?
Wanna not?
Why?
Come on, you've got nothin' to lose.
And you're getting a meal out of it!
It's tiring.
Why don't you just go with that friend?
No way!
If I went with a girl, I wouldn't
want her to fall in love with him, too!
Going with a guy friend
would get complicated,
so I'd rather go with someone
who has no interest in me!
Seriously, won't she go home already?
Refuses to share a fave
Besides, I have a girlfriend now.
I just can't.
Huh?! A new girl again?!
Your girlfriend turnover rate is too fast.
I'll never understand you popular guys.
Y'know, you're just gonna
break up with her anyway.
What's the harm of one little dinner?
I'm not breaking up with her.
Wha?!
Who is this sulking Kohaku?! So cute!
Before, he'd just laugh it off
and take it as a joke...
He does have a childish side.
Hey, what kind of person
is your current girlfriend?
What? Why?
No particular reason. Just wanted to know.
What kind...
She's proper, yet ditsy?
She quickly gets shy
and turns bright red...
She's old-school, stubborn, and acts
like a shonen manga hero sometimes...
Sometimes she's so bold,
it actually scares me.
Before I'd say she was "beautiful," but,
the more I get to know her,
the more I see these
inscrutable sides to her,
making it difficult to
form a full picture.
She likes sweet things.
Especially smooth red bean paste.
Your lackluster vernacular
is beyond hopeless.
How about this?
If you go out to dinner with me,
I'll tell you about a place
with delicious sweets!
Yeah, right, as if that
one's gonna work on you...
What, seriously?
You will?!
You're a good pal, Yoshiko!
Thanks!
Y-Yeah.
Yep. Yep!
All right, I'm gonna go change!
Wh-What was that face?!
Between this and that sulking face from earlier,
it's obvious that this isn't
the Kohaku I've known!
If I were to ask him, "What type of
person is she?" before, he'd be like...
Don't remember much.
And would answer with no interest at all!
The fact that he remembers that she
"likes sweet things" is amazing!
Just how cute is his new girlfriend?!
Hey, I'm ready to go.
Nasu Oyaji Curry
Oh. So, this is the place
you were talking about.
I see.
Oh, see?! Right there!
The hottie I was talking about!
Come to think of it,
Yoshiko did like those rugged,
older actors and such, didn't she?
Oh, my heart's pounding so hard!
Nasu Oyaji Curry
Weren't there two
other beauties there too?
What? Seriously?
Right, you only see the one
you're interested in.
Hmm.
Welp...
I get to see Yoi-chan, too, so...
Welcome!
Oh, you having curry today, too?
Huh? Where's Yoi-chan today?
Oh, she's off today.
What? Are you serious...
Too bad, huh?
Her friends came crying to her, so
she's helping them with their homework.
Hmm? Who's she?
Huh! Oh... Um, I'm...
Oh, just a childhood friend.
Oh, is that so?
Relax and enjoy your meal
today, too, all right?
Um, excuse me!
Coming!
Hey! What was that?!
You know him?!
Hmm? Yeah, I know him in a,
"He's my girlfriend's dad" sort of way?
Dad
Dad?
Huh?!
Shut up.
But... But, if he has a kid...
Then I've definitely got no chance.
Now, now.
Why don't you just choose a curry for now?
Her friends came crying to her,
so she took off... huh...
Wonder if she'd take a day off
if I came crying to her...
Wouldn't it be bad if Yoi-san saw this?
I didn't know what I was
doing at the time,
but I said things to Yoi-san that
encouraged her to be with this person.
No, this isn't any of my business.
Oh man. I'm stuffed!
You sure ate a lot, Yoshiko.
I'm just stress-eating!
Oh, sorry, phone call.
Could you cover me?
I'll pay you back later.
Yeah.
I'll wait in front of the convenience store.
All right.
Are you still awake?
Today
Did you get the homework done?
Am I being a creeper?
Today
Are you still awake?
Message deleted
Today
I'm not used to texting, so
I don't know what normal people say.
Your total comes to three thousand yen.
I'll pay with card.
Oh, hey.
Can I start heading to your place?
Huh?
I forgot something.
Keys, if you please!
Stop messing around, Yoshiko.
Sorry, sorry.
He should...
Don't you think you should
behave a bit more sincerely?
I don't like this person very much.
Hmm? What?
Whaddya mean by that?
You know, taking a girl to dinner
when you have a girlfriend.
No, I shouldn't be talking, either.
Anyway, does Yoi-san know about this?
You mean about Yoshiko?
It's not like that at all.
And this really has nothing
to do with you, does it?
He's spot-on.
What? You like Yoi-chan or something?
I've already told her...
how I feel.
What?
What do you mean by—
Kohaku!
Which way was the house again?
I can't figure it out by myself!
Yoshiko, you—
Oh, you're done paying already!
Let's go home!
H-Hey!
Come on, come on.
Thank you for the meal!
Thank you very much!
Oh, that's right.
My friend, who just called me, told me
about a delicious sweets shop, and...
What? What's wrong?
I've already told her how I feel.
Nothing.
What...
am I even...
I feel like I'm gradually
turning into a terrible person.
Oh, Oji-kun.
Can we figure out your work schedule
for next school term?
Oh, sure.
Ah... The morning light on the
first day of school is so bright!
I'm so glad we're able to see this day.
And it's all thanks to Yoi-sama.
You're going to bother people,
so please stop.
It really is all thanks to you, Yoi-chan.
I really thought we'd never
finish that homework!
That's right. That's right.
You're a lifesaver.
Okay, okay.
I'm not helping you during
winter break, okay?
'Kay!
Yep!
They don't seem like they
feel guilty at all.
But we didn't ruin your plans
or anything, right?
Like meeting up with Senpai and stuff?
Oh, we didn't have any, so it's fine.
What?
Hey, Yoi-chan, how many times have
you met with Senpai since Kobe?
He came to eat curry
at our place, so once?
Once?!
Wait, wait. You said he came to eat curry,
so you only saw him for about an hour?!
Well, probably...
You can't do that!
Oh, man. Poor Senpai!
I'll never understand you stubborn girls.
B-But I had my own plans, too.
And we're planning on having a
takoyaki party sometime, so...
But, Senpai was the one who
invited you to that, too, right?!
Huh? Oh, yes...
Yoi-chan, couldn't you try and
be more open for him?
That's right.
You were all about that contract, too.
You're lucky the Prince tolerates it.
Well, they do have a point.
We weren't able to hang
out much because of me.
Maybe I should be a little more proactive.
And... I did want
to see Senpai more, too.
I mean it really was my own fault, but...
It feels like, lately,
I always know where he is.
What's wrong?
No, it's nothing.
Oh, hey.
Did you bring that snack that you were
eating during our homework session?
I did! A new flavor came out!
Right on!
Sorry, you two.
Could you guys go on ahead?
Oh, that's right. I found
another delicious curry place!
Huh, where?
First floor of the station building!
Oh, didn't know there was one.
Are you still awake?
Message deleted
Today
Behind you. Please, turn around.
Yeah, it's like an Asian
café kinda store, and—
What, is it ethnic?
Yeah!
Sorry, gotta piss.
All right.
Yo.
It's been a while.
Hello.
H-Have you been well?
Yeah, super well.
How about you, Yoi-chan?
Oh, me too.
I mean, we did see each
other the other day.
We did, didn't we?
I need to be the proactive one here.
Hey—
Um—
Oh.
Please go ahead.
No, you, Yoi-chan.
But I...
If you don't, this conversation won't end.
After school today, would
you like to go somewhere?
Sure.
My pleasure.
Ah, I'm so happy!
Just the other day,
an acquaintance of mine told me
about a place with delicious sweets.
What was it again? You know.
That thing where they put
tiny cakes on a plate,
and has a name that
sounds like... "animation"?
Do you mean afternoon tea?
Yeah, that!
Genius!
Marvelous!
Beautiful!
I wonder if he's hooked on
complimenting me like that...
Only the "A" is the same, you know.
Anyway, let's plan
on meeting after school.
Okay!
Yay!
I've already told her how I feel.
Wow, amazing!
It's fancy!
But there's a lot of people waiting.
It really must be a popular place.
I-It's hot...
A-Are you all right, Senpai?!
That's right. He can't stand the heat!
I'm good, I'm good.
We're just standing
in line for a bit, right?
No sweat...
No, you're definitely sweating this one!
I don't wanna!
I finally get to go on a date with you.
I don't wanna go home!
What are you, a child?!
Then, how about we get it to go?
Where are we gonna eat it?
The park... would be hot.
A k-karaoke room?
Hmm, can't eat at the library...
I didn't bring my parasol with me today...
Hey, then.
Wanna come over to my place?
Huh?
Well, I'm not gonna force you, but...
To Senpai's...
house?
Isn't that...
taking one step ahead, before
even having the takoyaki party?!
No, I have to be the proactive one here!
I-I'll go!
Th-Thank you for having me...
I'll go get the table right now.
This is Senpai's room.
It's kind of empty...
Is this what a boy's room
typically looks like?
Oh.
Yoi-chan, sit here.
What?!
I don't have any seat pillows or anything.
But isn't that your bedding?
I don't mind.
But I do!
Then, how about something like this?
Now we're both on the bedding...
Why did I make it even more
nerve-wracking than it already was?!
Well, why don't we start eating?
Oh, yes! Let's!
I love sweet things,
but I'm so nervous, I don't
know if I'll be able to swallow.
What's wrong? Are you okay?
I'm... sorry.
The tea was hotter than I expected...
Did you burn yourself?
Let me see.
Oh, no, I'm fine!
Y'know, you don't have
to be so on-guard.
I'm just worried about you.
I-It's not that.
It's just that...
I don't think I can handle it.
Like, my heart already feels
like it's about to explode.
Sen...pai...
Huh?
I wonder how far this is going to go?
Senpai?
Um, what's wrong?
Hey, Yoi-chan.
Did something happen between
you and that part-time guy?
How... do you know about that?
The Empty Room
Translation:
Timing:
Editing:
Quality Control:
Final Quality Control:
Yukari Murase-Louden
Andy Ellis
Gabriella Alabanza
Salem Alabanza
Elizabeth Ellis